早上好 欢迎来到利蒙特旅店
Good morning.Welcome to the Freemont Inn.
有什么能为您效劳的吗?
How can I help you?
我想订个房间
I'd like a room,please.
噢 很抱歉 今晚客满了
Oh,I'm sorry,we're all full for tonight.
平安夜--旅店客满
Christmas Eve - no room at the inn.
谁能想到呢 对吧?
Who would have guessed,right?
你确定?
Are you sure?
无论什么房间都可以
I'll take anything you got.Please.
好吧 天气预报说会下雪
Well,forecast is calling for snow.
也许有客人取消预订
Maybe we've had some cancellations.
看样子只剩下高级套房 节假日价格
Looks like the only thing we have available is our Premiere Suite at the holiday rate.
我要了
I'll take it.
您不打算先问价格?
Don't you want to know how much first?
不用
No.
好的
Okay.
是我 我想我这边安全了
It's me. I think we're clear.
我下楼去接你
I'm on my way down to get you.
海军罪案调查处 第09季 第11集
今天是平安夜
Christmas Eve.
是的 Tony
Yes,it is,Tony.
我们运气太背
And we drew the short straw.
还要来值班 你们干嘛咧着嘴笑?
We have to work.So why are you smiling?
你没告诉我们Wendy给你寄圣诞贺卡了
You did not tell us that Wendy sent you a Christmas card.
哪个Wendy?
Wendy who?
你的Wendy 巴尔的摩Wendy
Your Wendy.Baltimore Wendy.
你前任未婚妻Wendy
Your former fiancee Wendy.
噢 那个啊 你们干嘛看我的圣诞贺卡?
Oh,yeah,that.What are you doing reading my Christmas cards?
卡片钉在你桌后的墙上
It was pinned on the wall behind your desk.
挂墙上不就是为了跟别人分享么
People usually do that so that others can enjoy them.
我还以为你和Wendy有些年头没...
I thought you and Wendy haven't talked in...
9年
Nine years.
你们想说什么?
What's your point?
上面说她和前夫去年离婚了
So it says here that she and her ex-husband divorced last year.
我看了 真替她难过
I read that.Too bad.Very sad.
她还邀请你明天共进圣诞早午餐 和她 以及她7岁的儿子 Fred
And she invited you to Christmas brunch tomorrow with her and her seven-year-old son,Fred.
真可爱
Pretty cute.
你去吗?
So you going to go?
不去 我已经把那段日子归于浮云
No. I think I'll relegate that part of my life to Christmas past.
我感觉Wendy是想和你重温旧梦
Well,I get the impression that Wendy may be looking to try again with you.
你这么认为?
You think so?
不 不 不 当然不是了
No,no,no,of course not.
我怎么会有放他鸽子的想法呢 Breena
I wouldn't dream of blowing him off,Breena.
我等不及和你爸共度美好时光
I can't wait to hang out with your dad.
是的
Yeah.
好的 我迟点再打给你
Okay,I-I'll call you later.
小Jim同学 这件可爱马甲怎么来的啊?
Tiny Jim,to what do we owe this lovely sweater vest?
谢谢你留意到了 Tony
Thank you,Tony,for noticing.
是Breena送我的礼物
It was a gift from Breena.
实际上 不幸的是 我送她的礼物随时会到
Actually,unfortunately,my gift to her should be arriving at any minute.
我答应他爸来城里度假的时候 带他来NCIS一游
I agreed to give her father a tour of NCIS,while he's in town for the holidays.
哟 很好么
Well,that is nice.
但我觉得Vance主任会否决这提议
Actually,I thought Director Vance would nix the idea.
你和Breena老爸相处不愉快?
You and Breena's dad do not get along?
上次Ed和我谈话 是我请求他把Breena嫁给我
The last time that Ed and I talked was when I asked for his permission to marry Breena.
他笑了
He laughed.
他笑得太厉害 接着又哭了
And then he cried from laughing so hard.
然后突然鸦雀无声
Then he got really quiet.
他来这里干嘛?
So why is he coming here?
Breena希望我们在婚礼前 能建立起良好的关系
Breena wanted us to bond before the wedding.
她觉得他最在意我的工作
She thinks that his main problem with me is my job.
验尸精灵
Autopsy gremlin.
不是吧 等着他进来撞见我们在谈这个?
Yeah,if we could keep that kind of talk to a minimum while he's here?
我已经用上最美妙的词汇了
I say it with the utmost respect.
我明白 我懂 但是Ed不明白
I know that,I know that,but Ed doesn't.
他觉得我困在了一份工资又低
You guys,he actually thinks that I'm stuck in some government job
工作时间又长的政府工作
which pays too little and requires too many hours.
事实如此 把屁股从我桌上挪开
You are. Get off my desk.
带装备
Grab your gear.
啊 帅的 要去开工了
Ah,yes. Uh,duty calls.
我得打电话给Ed取消约会
So I'd better call Ed and cancel.
等等 你哪儿都不用去 Palmer
Hold on.You're not going anywhere,Palmer.
家庭第一
Family first.
马甲不错
Nice sweater.
圣诞快乐 Palmer
Merry Christmas,Palmer.
海军上校Jake Marsden
Navy Captain Jake Marsden.
驻守查尔斯顿 南卡罗来纳州
Stationed in Charleston,South Carolina.
根据驾照资料 他也住在那里
According to his driver's license,he also lives there.
游客
Tourist.
前台说他急着去房间
Desk clerk said he was in a hurry to get to his room.
这么多伤口 是我也会急着躲
For good reason,judging by those wounds.
血溅痕迹表明他中枪时站在这里
Blood spatter indicates that he was standing about here when multiple gunshots went through him.
子弹有不同口径
Looks like different calibers.
多把枪
Multiple weapons.
多个枪手
Multiple shooters.
旁边的客人都没听到枪声
Guests did not hear anything that sounded like gunshots.
枪手用了消音器 也没留下指纹和证据
The gunmen must have used silencers and no fingerprints or evidence were left behind.
职业杀手 - 行家
- Pro job. - Humbug.
代客泊车要25元
25 bucks for valet parking.
干嘛不直接去抢劫
Highway robbery.
说实话 不能排除挡路抢劫
Actually,I wouldn't rule out a highway robbery.
看 车窗被砸了
Look at that - passenger window's been blown out.
子弹孔
Bullet holes.
看样子侧边被撞过
Looks like it's been sideswiped.
泊车人说发现的时候就是这样的
Valet said they found it this way.
这是他们的官方回答 不是吗?
That's what they always say,isn't it?
嘿 看样子死者是海军
Hey,thought our dead guy was Navy.
都没听你说过为什么 和Wendy解除婚约的
You know,you never mentioned why you broke off the engagement with Wendy.
谁说我解约了?
Who said I broke it off?
什么 结婚当天她扔下你跑了?
What,she leave you at the altar?
我没说过
I didn't say that either.
雅虎~~~
Yahoo.
海军水手袋里惊现女人内衣
Marine sea bag - women's bra.
要么我们死去的海军上校性别有问题 要么他不是一个人出门的
Either our dead Navy captain was having an identity crisis,or he wasn't traveling alone.
David探员 帮我把上校包起来好吗?
Agent David,would you give me a hand in wrapping up the captain?
我太早答应给Palmer放半天假了
I was premature in giving Mr. Palmer the morning off.
如果是酒店经理 告诉他我不会拖着尸体过走廊的
If that's the hotel manager,tell him we won't take the body through his lobby.
Gibbs 电话不是来自酒店内的
Gibbs.The call's not coming from inside the hotel.
看这区号 是北马里兰州
The area code - that's northern Maryland.
Jake 是你吗?
Jake,is that you?
发生了什么事?
What happened?
我也想知道
Well,I'd like to know the same thing.
你杀了他 对吗?
You killed him,didn't you?
他死了 但不是我干的
He's dead,but I didn't do it.
你是谁?
Who is this?
你又是谁?
你是警察? - NCIS
- are You a cop? - NCIS.
证明给我看 - 怎么证明?
- Prove it. - How?
如果你没撒谎 自然会知道我是谁
If you are who you say,you'll figure it out.
海军上校 Jake Marsden
Navy Captain Jake Marsden.
单身 没有家庭 人见人爱
Single,no family,well liked.
从他队友那里得知 他一心只埋头工作
But according to his unit,the only thing he made time for was his job.
真悲哀
Kind of sad,really.
所以你该考虑去和Wendy吃饭
Precisely why you should reconsider lunch with Wendy.
McGee和我查过Marsden的车
McGee and I searched Marsden's car.
对女伴的身份毫无头绪
Nothing that I.D.'s the female travel companion.
可能就是她打的电话
Perhaps she was our mystery caller.
McGee 酒店电话记录
McGee,hotel phone records.
案发前 受害者从房间里往外打过电话
Prior to the murder,our victim made one outgoing phone call from the hotel room.
打给登在他名下的手机
To a cell phone registered in his own name.
跟踪得到么?
You track it?
关机了
It's been turned off.
房间来电呢?
Incoming to the room?
我查了后台记录
I already ran a back-trace.
打入酒店的电话来自... - 嘿 各位
- The call to The hotel came from... - Hiya,team.
我来介绍下我的未来岳父大人 Ed Slater
Just came to introduce my future father-in-law Ed Slater.
时机不对?
Is this a bad time?
没事 继续
Go ahead.
好吧 Ed?
Okay.Ed?
这位...
This...
呃 Slater先生 这位是我们的英雄领袖 特别探员Leroy Jethro Gibbs
uh,Mr.Slater,this is our fearless leader,Special Agent Leroy Jethro Gibbs.
还有我们的特别探员 Anthony Tony DiNozzo
Over here we have Special Agent Anthony "Tony" DiNozzo.
别说了 James 我又不是来查户口的
Stop speaking,James.I don't need their dossiers.
在这里待几个小时就走
Only here for a few hours.
但很高兴认识你们
But what a pleasure.
欢迎来到NCIS Slater先生
Welcome to NCIS,Mr.Slater.
真不知道怎么夸你的未来女婿 和他的尽忠职守
Can't say enough about your future son-in-law and his work ethic here.
所以我才过来 对吧?
Yes,well,that's why I'm here,isn't it?
来看看 如果我女儿嫁给James 是只嫁给了他
To make sure that if my daughter marries James,she gets him,
而不是在衙门里工作的 带着官僚作风的爷们 懂不?
not the bureaucratic baggage that comes with a government job,you know?
不懂 - 不懂?
- No. - No?
是不懂
No.
不好意思 你刚才是不是说 "如果她嫁给他"
I'm sorry,did you just say "if she marries him"?
你就想着吧 我来问你 特别超级探员 Gibbs
Big if.Let me ask you something,Special Super Agent Gibbs.
你是唯一让员工在平安夜加班的领导吗
Are you the only team leader who makes his folks work Christmas Eve?
山姆大叔让你往东 你不敢往西 君让臣死 臣非死不可
I guess when Uncle Sam calls you answer,even when he calls collect.
我觉着我们应该全面参观一下这地方
I think we've seen all we should in the squad room.
不如我带你...
Why don't I show you...
看看其他地方?
anyplace else?
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
真是个有礼貌的人
He's a pleasant man.
McGee 打进酒店的电话
McGee,phone call to the hotel.
追踪了号码
Traced the number.
电话来自于马里兰 菲尔莫 从奥特莱斯商场的公用电话打出
The call came from a courtesy phone at an outlet mall in Fillmore,Maryland.
距这儿两小时车程
That's two hours from here.
如果神秘女人在酒店出现 为什么又去那里?
If our mystery woman was at the hotel,how did she get out there?
找到她 弄清楚
Find her. Find out.
现在调出商场的监控录像
Pulling mall security footage now.
本来是要参观国家圣诞树 结果在肯尼迪中心碰上胡桃夹子
A visit to the national Christmas tree followed by a production of The Nutcracker at the Kennedy Center.
真悲催 上校 你的华盛顿之旅实在是
Sadly,Captain,your visit to D.C.was,
太过简要而不能领略我们城市的假日风采
well,much too brief to enjoy our city's holiday fare.
他经常自言自语?
He always talk to himself?
实际上 Slater先生 我是在与死者交流
Actually,Mr.Slater,I am conversing with our victim.
呃 真是浪费时间
Well,it's a waste of time.
我认为 死了就是死了
In my experience,the dead are dead.
你这话是什么意思?
And what experience would that be?
Ed经营一间殡仪馆
Ed owns a funeral home.
我猜这就是Breena热衷于防腐的原因吧?
I guess that is where Breena got her passion for embalming,huh?
我以前经常跟她说...
I always used to tell her...
你又话多了 James
You're speaking again,James.
我是个职业殡葬承办人 Mallard医生
Uh,I'm a professional mortician,Dr.Mallard.
那你应该知道每个人都有 自己的故事要讲 只要你问对了问题
Then you should know that everybody has a unique story to tell if asked the right questions.
也许吧 不过你这么滔滔不绝的 这可怜的家伙也插不上嘴 是吧?
Maybe,but,uh,as much as you talk,this poor guy can hardly get a word in edgewise.Huh?
我看你俩最好在外面等
I think it best if you two wait outside.
是啊 我可以等
Yeah,I'll second that.
为啥... - 批准动议
- Look,why... - Motion carries.
还有很多东西要看
Lot of things to see.
很有意思 是吧?
This is fun,huh?
Duck 有什么线索?
Duck,what do you got?
确认了死因
Confirmation of cause of death.
还有这个 当我脱下上校的衣服 发现这个在裤子口袋里面
And this - when I took off the captain's clothes I found it stuffed deep in a pants pocket.
干的血迹 他的?
Dried blood.His?
得让Abby检测
That's up to Abby.
但除了子弹伤口很新鲜以外
But apart from the bullet wounds which are fresh,
在其他地方也没发现有外伤痕迹
there's no other exterior signs of trauma anywhere.
血迹也可能来自于失踪女人
Blood could be from our missing woman.
如果是的话 就说明她不仅在逃命
Well,if it were,it would suggest that in addition to being on the run,
可能也受伤了
she could also be wounded.
Abbs
Abbs.
- Gibbs 来实验室? - 好 马上来
- Gibbs,coming to the lab? - Yeah,I'm on my way.
Abbs?
Abby?
在这后面
Back here.
谢天谢地 只有你
Oh,thank goodness it's just you.
Jimmy和他那二逼岳父窜来窜去 到处散布些傻逼言论和圣诞衰话
Jimmy and his Grinch-in-law have been stalking the halls spreading ill-will and yuletide yuckness.
他在大厅时是不是要和你吵架?
Hey,did he try to pick a fight with you in the squad room?
没有 他只是一个...
No,he's just being a...
不合时宜 不可理喻地粗俗之人
Unseasonably and unreasonably rude.
他马上就当岳父了
He's being a father-in-law to be.
如果他明白事理的话
Well,if he knows what's good for him,
他就应该远离我的地盘 至少20尺之外再唱祝酒词
he's not going to come a-wassailing within at least 20 feet of my leaves of green.
发现什么?
What do we got?
McGee发来的商场监控录像 还有卡罗尔镇专营商场里的好人们
Mall security footage courtesy of McGee and the kind people at the Carroll County Outlet Shoppes.
那简直是卡罗尔之宝
"The Jewel of Carroll County."
我觉得在卡罗尔也没啥可做的...
I don't think there's a lot to do in Carroll County...
找到打电话的女人了吗?
Did you find our female caller?
我实现你第一个圣诞许愿 Gibbs
I'm granting you your first Christmas wish,Gibbs.
那就是她 给酒店打电话
That is her,calling the hotel.
如果Ducky发现的那块血迹是她的 不过她看上去不象受伤的样子
If the blood on the rag that Ducky found is hers,she doesn't appear wounded.
查到身份吗?
Get an I.D.?
没有 不过我知道她在哪
No,but I think I know where she is.
看她转向摄像头
Watch when she turns towards the camera.
假使如你所说 你会有办法查清楚
"If you are who you say,you will figure it out."
购物袋? - 没错
- The bag? - Yeah.
是一间女式服装店的
It's from a women's clothing store.
她知道我们会看监控
She knew that we would watch the security footage.
她想让你去找到她 Gibbs
She wants you to come find her,Gibbs.
干得漂亮
Nice work.
让DiNozzo与当地警方联系 和我们在那里汇合
Tell DiNozzo to have local P.D. meet us there.
欢迎来到卡罗尔 你们一定是NCIS
Welcome to Carroll County. You must be NCIS.
外面确实下雪了 是吧?
Snow's really coming down out there,huh?
所以他们派了个商场保安?
So they,uh...sent a mall cop,huh?
不 长官 我是本县副警长
No,sir. I'm a county deputy.
Billy McCormick警官
Officer Billy McCormick.
你们打电话的时候只有我当值
I was the only one on duty when you called.
能告诉我们最新情况吗 副警长?
You got an update,Deputy?
是的 长官
Yes,sir.
我仔细检查了商场 还没发现情绪不正常的人
I canvassed the store,but haven't found anyone in distress.
你们找的人肯定已经离开了
Whoever you're looking for must have left already.
你看得有多仔细?
How hard did you look?
我跟每一个单独逛街的人都聊过
I talked to every single solitary person.
那更衣室的呢?
What about in the dressing rooms?
呃 没有 这是个女式服装店 所以...
Well,no.This is a women's clothing store,so...
是啊 我们在寻找一位女性
Yeah,yeah. We-we are looking for a woman,though.
疏散所有人
Get everybody out of here.
马上办 老大
Will do,boss.
干得不错 不错
Good job,though.Good job.
请注意
Can I have your attention,please.
所有人立即离开店内
Everyone needs to leave the store immediately.
请从这边疏散
Exit's this way,please.
联邦探员 快离开这
Federal agents.Go on,get out of here.
好吧
Okay.
NCIS
NCIS.
假证件我不是没见过
Yeah,I've seen fake credentials before.
交出你的武器
Hand over your weapons.
只有一个办法能让海军交枪
There's only one way to get a Marine's weapon.
对此你了解多少?
What do you know about it?
你是海军陆战队员?
You a leatherneck?
不然你以为我在哪儿剪的这发型?
Where do you think I got this haircut?
如果杀Jake的凶手不是你俩 那就意味着他们还在外虎视耽耽
Well,if you two aren't the ones that killed Jake,that means that they're still out there.
你觉得他们也在追杀你?
You think they're after you,too?
我知道他们是谁
I know they are.
Jake不是目标 我才是
Jake wasn't the target - I am.
我是在青年营获得的ITS(单兵训练标准)
Did my I.T.S. at Camp Lejeune.
你也是吗 Reynolds上尉?
You like it there,Lieutenant Reynolds?
叫我Emma
Call me Emma.
是的 我也是
And yes,I did.
真希望我现在也在那里
Wish like hell I was there now.
天气越来越糟 老大
Weather's getting pretty bad,boss.
拖车堵在高速上 一辆接一辆的
Tractor trailer jackknifed on the highway.It's bumper to bumper.
你出去买咖啡了 DiNozzo?
You out getting coffee,DiNozzo?
不 不 这是给孕妇准备的热可可...
No,no,no,this is hot chocolate for the preg...
给上尉
the Lieutenant.
大家听着 我不需要特殊对待
Listen,everyone,I don't want any special treatment.
我首先是个陆战队员 其次才是孕妇
I'm a Marine first and pregnant second.
噢...哇
Oo-rah.
噢是的
Oo-right.
我很高兴接受特殊待遇
Well,I will gladly take the special treatment.
我想要杯加点棉花糖的 小块点的
I like mine with extra marshmallows-- the little tiny ones,please.
你当我是谁 你的家养小精灵?
Who do you think I am,your elf?
其实我也想要一杯加棉花糖的
Actually,I'll take one with marshmallows,too.
鉴于你说你不想被特别对待...
Thought you said you didn't want any special...
加棉花糖的马上就来
Extra marshmallows coming up.
谁在追杀你 上尉?
So who is after you,Lieutenant?
不知道
I don't know.
我八个半月前才回国
Only ever been a squared-away Marine until eight and a half months ago.
以前我一直驻扎在喀布尔城外
I was stationed outside Kabul.
我们小组负责训练阿富汗当地士兵
Our unit was training local Afghan soldiers.
其中一个会讲英语
One of them spoke English.
他叫Amir
His name was Amir.
事情变得浪漫了
Things got romantic.
起码在那种鬼地方不会觉得浪漫
At least what passes for romantic in that hellhole.
在条件差的地方是需要勇气的
Sand can get in some pretty inconvenient places.
被纪律处分了?
Any disciplinary action?
我负全责
I took responsibility.
我被扣两个月工资 遣送回本土
C.O. made me forfeit two months pay and sent me stateside.
以为事情就此打住
Thought that was it.
但是?
But?
上周 我注意到被一辆黑色SUV跟踪
Last week,I noticed I was being followed by a black SUV.
我摆脱了它 然后另一辆车又出现了
I would shake it,and then another one would show up.
有多个人在跟踪你?
Multiple people were following you?
三个人 分别有越野车
Three men - separate SUV's.
我记下了其中一辆的车牌号
I got one of the license numbers.
登记在国防部的名下
It was registered to the Department of Defense.
给McGee打电话 让他跟踪调查
Call McGee.Have him follow up.
所以你跟Marsden一起逃出城来?
So you skipped town with Marsden?
Jake是我的老朋友
Jake's an old friend.
他建议开车送我去我父母 在俄亥俄州的家里
He offered to drive me to my parents' place in Ohio.
从那时候事情变得疯狂了
That's when things got crazy.
他们跟踪了你
They followed you.
他们试图把我们挤下公路
They tried to run us off the road.
玻璃破的时候我割伤了手
I cut my hand when the window broke.
然后我们甩掉了他们 但是我开始感觉头晕 于是我们去了旅馆
And we lost them.But I started feeling woozy,so we went to the hotel.
当Jake没有下来的时候 我就知道我必须要从那儿逃出来
When Jake didn't come down,I knew that I had to get out of there.
你为什么不给警察打电话呢?
Why didn't you call the police?
如果这些家伙是政府的人 他们也会派当地执法部门来找我们的
If these guys were government,they would send local LEOs looking for us,too.
我不知道这是为什么 还要持续多久
I don't know what this is about or how far up this goes.
你可以相信我们
Well,you can trust us.
谢谢
Thank you.
孩子的父亲现在在哪儿?
Where's the father now?
- 孩子的父亲去世了? - 是的
- The baby's father's dead? - Yes.
Amir Mayat五月份 死于路边炸弹爆炸
Amir Mayat died in an IED explosion back in May.
报告称 Reynolds上尉 在事故以后就去休假了
Says here,Lieutenant Reynolds went on leave after the incident.
那她的公公婆婆呢?
What about the in-laws?
他们应该对关心一下孩子吧
I mean,they must have some interest in the child.
根据她的说法 怀孕的事情她和Amir是瞒着他的家人的
According to her statement,she and Amir kept the pregnancy a secret from his family.
你看 McGee探员 所有这些都在她的档案里面
You know,Agent McGee,all of this is in her personnel file.
你不需要我念给你听的
You don't need me to read it to you.
不要挂
Hang on.
你到底想要知道什么?
What is it you really want to know?
这份档案是国防部唯一一份关于 Reynolds上尉的文件吗?
Is that file the only record DOD has on Lieutenant Reynolds?
你是什么意思?
What do you mean?
有人跟踪了她
Someone's having her followed.
你认为是我们?
You think it's us?
我们是国防部 又不是中情局
We're DOD,not CIA.
我们一般不会做这种事情
We don't usually do that kind of thing.
一般
Usually.
我们干吗要关心Reynolds 在她产假的时候做什么呢?
Why would we care what Reynolds does on her maternity leave?
我们有理由相信三名持枪人员 利用注册在国防部名下的车辆
We have reason to believe that three gunmen using vehicles registered
杀死了一名海军上校 而且现在在跟踪Reynolds上尉
to the DOD murdered a Navy captain and are now after the Lieutenant.
你想说什么?
What are you suggesting?
你知道我们在这个城里 注册了多少辆车吗?
Do you know how many vehicles we have registered in this city?
几千辆 而且常常被偷
Thousands.They get stolen all the time.
我很乐意为你查一下我们的数据库
I'd be happy to check our database for you.
我明白 先生 但是你还是没有回答我的问题
I understand that,sir,but you're not answering my question.
Reynolds上尉是不是在你的监视之下?
Is Lieutenant Reynolds on your radar?
McGee探员 现在唯一在我的监视之下 的就是圣诞老人了
Agent McGee,the only thing on my radar right now is Santa Claus.
我明白了 先生
I understand,sir.
但是如果你有任何 关于Reynolds中尉的消息 请告知我们
But you will let us know if you find out anything on Lieutenant Reynolds?
即便是我有消息 在没有授权的情况下我也不能告诉你
Even if I did,I couldn't tell you without authorization.
圣诞快乐
Feliz Navidad.
是 Abbs
Yeah,Abbs.
Gibbs 你还在那边干什么?
Gibbs,what are you still doing there?
雪坠落得比我的圣诞情绪还要快
The snow is falling faster than my holiday spirit.
一名怀孕的陆战队员在圣诞节被追捕
There's a pregnant Marine being hunted on Christmas.
天堂和大自然都不唱歌了
Heaven and nature are not singing.
我在等消息 还有州警察派来的一个护卫队 就告诉我你有什么发现
Well,I'm waiting on intel and an escort from state troopers.Just tell me what you got.
Reynolds上尉孩子的父亲 -Amir Mayat-的背景
Background on Lieutenant Reynolds' baby daddy--
他可不是个贫穷的农民
Amir Mayat - and he is not a poor farmer.
Mayat的部落控制着喀布尔城外 一大片重要的土地
The Mayat tribe controls a massive and critical land parcel just outside of Kabul.
家族资产
Family's wealthy.
非常大
Extremely.
而且Amir是唯一的男性继承人
And Amir was the sole male heir.
直到他被杀死
Until he was killed.
对 如果Emma有了个男孩 那么...
Yes. And if Emma has a boy,then...
这个孩子就继承了一切
The kid inherits everything.
甚至是王位
Practically royalty.
最少也是极度的财富
At least extremely valuable.
这也就解释了为什么中尉 到现在还活着
Well,that explains why the Lieutenant's still alive.
哦 对 对 对 他们不想让她死
Oh,yeah,yeah.They don't want her dead.
他们需要这孩子活着
They want the baby alive.
这解释不了为什么国防部会参与进来
It does not explain DOD's involvement.
这有可能 老大
This might,boss.
什么 McGee?
What,McGee?
我做了些深入的挖掘
I did some digging.
穿过了国防部的防火墙
I tunneled under the DOD firewall.
发现美国在阿富汗的军事力量正试图 建造一条通过Mayat家土地的贸易公路
Turns out U.S. military forces in Afghanistan are trying to build a trade highway through Mayat land.
这对镇压武装分子和 阻止武器走私非常重要
It's vital for fighting insurgents and stopping weapons shipments.
但是部落的长老们并不合作
And the tribal elders aren't cooperating.
需要国防部花费数百万美元
Which is costing the DOD millions of dollars.
但是如果项目失败 他们可能失去的更多
And if the project goes under,they lose even more.
他们需要谈判筹码
Well,they need a bargaining chip.
这个小婴儿继承人
The little baby heir.
根据长子继承权 他会成为Mayat部落的头领
By birthright,he'll be the head of the Mayat tribe.
他们得到了孩子 就得到了土地
They have the kid,they have the land.
我们能证实吗?
Can we prove it?
我还没找到任何实际的证据 将国防部和我们的三名杀手联系起来
Well,I still can't find anything concrete connecting the DOD and our three kings.
继续找
Keep looking.
他们关在里面给有多久了?
How long have they been back there?
还不够久
Not long enough.
开门
Door.
我听不到他们在说什么
I can't hear a word they're saying.
如果你不对她的纹身做那样的评价 我们也不会在这儿耗时间
Well,if you hadn't made that remark about her tattoos,we wouldn't be in time out.
我还有六分钟的下班
I still got six minutes left.
你应该知道在私营企业工作你能挣到
You do know that there are jobs in the private sector where
比这多两倍的工资 而且同样可以六点钟到家 对吧?
you could make twice as much money and still be home by 6:00,right?
没怎么考虑过
Hadn't really thought about that.
你可以开始考虑一下
Well,maybe you should start.
而且我只是跟她说 有纹身的女孩比较放荡
And all I said to her was that girls with tattoos are easy.
每个人都知道的
Everyone knows that.
出什么问题了吗 Gibbs探员? 你发现什么了?
Is something wrong,Agent Gibbs?What did you find out?
我会在出去的路上告诉你
I'll tell you on the way out.
车停在后面 老大 他们开始关闭公路了
Car's out back,boss.They started closing the highways.
可能到早晨才能开放了
It's not going to open till the morning.
看来我们只能靠自己了
Looks like we're on our own.
走小路?
Back roads?
要是有人跟踪我们呢?
What if someone follows us?
不能再等了
Can't wait any longer.
我要件武器
I want a weapon.
你不需要 你有我们
You don't need one.You got us.
不用保护我 我是我们排的头号射手
Don't patronize me.I was the top shot in my platoon.
你觉得那狗治安官见过真正的战斗吗?
You think Deputy Dog's ever seen actual combat?
我有三次海外驻扎经历
I did three tours.
不过Barney Fife在哪儿?
Where is Barney Fife anyway?
我以为他跟你在一起呢
I thought he was out back with you.
- 对不起 - 闭嘴
- I'm sorry. - Shut up!
- 他突然就出现了 - 闭嘴
- He came out of nowhere. - Shut up!
他是那三个人之一
He's one of the three.
NCIS 放他走
NCIS. Let him go.
把那个女人给我
Give me the woman!
不 不可能的
No,it's not going to happen.
我不想伤害他
I don't want to hurt him.
我很清楚你想要什么
I know exactly what you want.
放下武器
Drop your weapon.
你没有资格提出要求
You are in no position to make demands.
我没有 但是她有
I'm not,but she is.
除非你今天就想死 放下武器
Unless you want to die today,put it down.
现在!
Now!
DiNozzo 你和治安官带他回去
DiNozzo,you and the deputy take him back.
我们和上尉一起
We got the Lieutenant.
好的 回海军大院见
All right,meet you back at the Navy yard.
开始行动 老大
On it,boss.
这是怎么回事?
What's that all about?
剪枝机事故?
Hedge trimmer accident?
考验 - 什么?
- Proof. - of what?
胆量
Nerve.
俄罗斯监狱团伙中常见的入伙仪式
Initiation ritual common in Russian prison gangs.
你其他的朋友也丢了指头吗?
Any of your other friends missing fingers?
你自己去看吧
You will see for yourself.
这是什么意思?
What does that mean?
意思是我们要赶紧离开这儿
Means we're getting the hell out of here.
小心脑袋
Watch your head.
啊 你在这儿
Ah,there you are.
我听说大家正带着嫌犯回程呢
I hear the team is on its way back with a suspect.
你还有其他消息吗
Have you heard anything more?
没有
No.
只是在等Ed
Just been waiting on Ed.
怎么了 Palmer先生?
What's the matter,Mr.Palmer?
就是有点受打击吧 我想
Just a bit overwhelmed,I guess.
无论我做什么 都会鼓励我
My own father was only ever encouraging to me no matter what I did.
可是Ed Ed就像"圣诞颂歌" 里的小气财神一样讨厌
And Ed,Ed is like Ebenezer Scrooge at the beginning of the book.
一点小小的建议
A bit of advice.
别让一个鼠目寸光之徒的诋毁之言 影响到你的生活
Don't let the disparaging remarks of a myopic individual influence your life.
没错 就是这个
See,that's just it.
他终于对我说了些好听的
He finally said something nice to me.
真的?
Really?
他的殡仪馆可以给我提供了一份工作
He offered me a job at his funeral home.
他说 Breena和我可以一同共事
He said that Breena and I could work together.
最终接管生意
Eventually take over the business.
真是如此?
Really?
这是你想要的吗?
Is that what you want?
我? 不 不是 我喜欢NCIS
Me?No. No,I love NCIS.
可是我想让Breena高兴
But I want to make Breena happy.
医生...如果这是唯一的方法可怎么办?
Doctor... what if this is the only way?
Breena会因为你的快乐而快乐
Breena will be happy if you are happy.
告诉Ed先生这句话
Tell that to Mister Ed.
俄国雇佣兵想要我那未出世的孩子
Russian mercenaries want to take my unborn child
因为他是在阿富汗土地的唯一继承人?
because he's the only heir to land in Afghanistan?
我们相信枪手可能受雇于 政府内部的某人
We believe the gunmen may have been hired by someone inside the government.
为什么?
Why?
因为那块土地对能否在阿富汗取得胜利至关重要
Because that land may be key in winning or losing Afghanistan.
我开始意识到为什么Amir 疏远自己的家庭
I'm starting to understand why Amir distanced himself from his family.
出了什么事?
What happened?
引擎有问题?
Is it the engine?
俄罗斯人
The Russians.
这里没信号
There is no signal out here.
前面有亮光
There's a light up ahead.
哦 上帝
Oh,God.
你觉得我们能修理好它吗?
Do you think we can fix it?
我不这么觉得
I don't think we've got a choice.
我在转弯那儿看到个车库
I saw a garage around back.
我帮忙推车
I'll help push.
别推
Don't push.
你们怎么还没走?
You guys are still here,huh?
呃 我是Ed的车夫 严格来说 我还没完成工作 所以...
Well,I'm Ed's ride,and technically I'm still on duty,so...
工作
Duty.
有没有Gibbs的消息? - 还没
- any word from Gibbs? - Not yet.
你觉得他们怎么花了这么长时间?
What do you think's taking them so long?
我不知道 我们分开走的
I don't know.We left separately.
肯定走的不是一条路
Must have taken a different route.
可能被坏天气困住了
Could have hit bad weather.
有没有试过给他打手机?
Did you try calling him?
Abby每五分钟就给他打一次电话
Abby's been calling his cell every five minutes.
无人接听 而且从这儿到巴尔的摩 的陆线也因为冰雪中断了
Nothing.And the land lines are down from here to Baltimore due to ice.
幸好网还没有断
Lucky we still have Internet.
查到我们断指男的身份了吗?
Find anything to finger our fingerless man?
我搜索了他的剩余指纹
I ran his remaining prints.
名字是Veli Tupolev
Name is Veli Tupolev.
在本土没有记录 但在国际刑警可是大相径庭
No record in the States but Interpol's a different story.
让我猜猜 一个受训过的无惧隆冬 并把牢底坐穿的俄罗斯佣兵?
Let me guess - a trained mercenary who's used to hard Russian winters and even harder Russian prisons?
差不多
Pretty much.
你打算怎么让他开口?
How do you want to break him?
呃...
Well...
怎么了?我饿了
What?I was hungry.
我可没料到会当了人质
Didn't know I'd be held hostage.
等一下
Wait a second.
那些是人力部Hollander 的手工圣诞饼干?
Are those Hollander's homemade Christmas cookies from HR?
她今年有没有做糖浆?
Did she make molasses this year?
她做啦 而且味道好极了
She did,and they were good.
我们需要征用这些
We're gonna need to commandeer these.
警察事务
Police business.
我觉得我有招儿来让咱们的坏脾气圣诞老人开口说话了
I think I have a way to break our Bad Santa.
用什么 饼干?
With what,cookies?
你打算怎么做 用糖衣炮弹击垮他?
What are you gonna do,sugarboard him?
还以为他们是专业人士呢
Thought you said they were pros.
喷射器管出了问题
Injector rail was damaged.
汽油渗漏到歧管 引起了火源
Fuel leaked into the manifold and caught fire.
没错 我试着重接些线路
Yeah,I'm gonna have to try and redo some wiring.
我去看看他们有什么
I'll see what they got.
电脑还是不能用 不过我在试
The phones are still out,but I'll keep checking.
或者如果你那边需要帮助 我对汽车有一手
Or if you want any help in there,I know my way around a car.
坐会儿 休息一下
Well,sit down.Rest.
喝点水
Have some fluids.
不用 我已经喝了
No. I already did.
我-我在付款处留了些钱
I-I left a couple of bucks on the register.
感觉就那么拿走很怪
Felt weird just to take it.
别担心 会没事的
Don't worry about it; it's gonna be fine.
这可和我计划的平安夜天壤之别 Gibbs探员
This is not exactly the Christmas Eve that I had planned on,Agent Gibbs.
实话说 我对这些都没料到
Actually,I hadn't planned on any of this.
Amir...
孩子...
the baby...
人们想要偷走他
people trying to steal him.
他?
Him?
我记得你说过不知道男女
I thought you said you didn't know.
我不知道 可是我有感觉
I don't,but I can tell.
根据他现在踢打我的力道来看...
Oh,and judging by the way he's punching and kicking me right now...
- 过来 - ...我觉得他也会加入海军
- Come on. - ...I think he's gonna be a Marine,too.
坐下
Sit down.
我一心就只想加入海军
I just wanted to be a Marine.
我猜其他人肯定不止这个想法
I guess someone else had other plans.
是啊 不是第一次了
Yeah.Wouldn't be the first time.
你有孩子吗 Gibbs先生?
Do you have kids,Agent Gibbs?
曾经有个女儿
Had a daughter.
她出生时候你在吗?
Were you there when she was born?
外派
Deployed.
我觉得也得就靠我一人了
Well,I guess I kind of have to be there for mine.
我不是在抱怨
Not that I'm complaining.
只是...
It's just...
我或许会...
I might be...
害怕?
Scared?
你在说啥?
The hell you say?
即便害怕也没事
It's all right if you are.
这可跟军人法条不一致
Not according to the Corps.
也就是为什么我喜欢当海军的原因
That's what I like about being a Marine.
程序
The procedures.
准则
The code.
我喜欢能触及到的期望
I like having a measurable set of expectations.
我可以很骄傲地说自己做得有多好 但是怀着孩子...
I could always tell how good I was doing,but with this...
我怎么知道?
how do I know?
你不知道
You don't.
可是你能感觉到
But you'll be able to tell.
我觉得这小子告诉我现在该吃饭了
Right now,I think this guy is telling me that it's time to eat.
好...这样的话...
Well... in that case...
算我请的
This one's on me.
谢谢
Thank you.
你知道吗 Wendy做的姜人饼是 全天下最好吃的
You know,Wendy used to make the most kick-ass snickerdoodle.
下面我们要进行是或不是的问答 好让我们了解你的基准线
I'm going to start with a series of true or false statements to give us a baseline.
你们在说什么?
What are you talking about?
就把这个想象成有饼干吃的测谎试验
Just think of it as like a lie detector test with cookies.
你只需要坐在这儿吃就行了
You just have to sit there and eat.
好了 我们开始
Okay,here we go.
你的发色是紫色
Your hair is purple.
你的手指都在
You have all your fingers.
你尾随Emma Reynolds中尉 企图绑架她的孩子
You were following Lieutenant Emma Reynolds with the intention of abducting her baby.
哦 犹豫
Oh,hesitation.
我看到了犹豫
I see the hesitation.
是啊 他犹豫了 - 没错
- Yeah,He did. - Yeah.
确认了 犹豫
Confirming hesitation.
没有 我可没犹豫
No,no,I did not hesitate.
我不知道你该说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你确定?
You sure about that?
你从没有犯罪
You've never committed a crime.
你最喜欢的颜色是粉色
Your favorite color is pink.
你受雇于美国国防部的某人
You were hired by someone at the United States Department of Defense.
所以你实际上是为政府效力!
So you really are working for the government!
不 我不知道你在说什么
No. I don't know what you're talking about.
你确定?
Sure about that?
那你就是为阿富汗的Mayat部落效力
So then you must be working for the Mayat tribe in Afghanistan.
我觉得这是代表咱们说对了
I'll take that as a yes.
不是 我只是被饼干噎到
No. I just choke on cookie.
这不能说明什么
It does not mean anything.
哦 这很能说明问题
Oh,it speaks volumes.
太愚蠢了!
This is stupid!
你们只是在努力搅乱我的思维!
You're just trying to mess with my head!
如果不是真的 那你为什么又如此沮丧?
Then why are you getting so upset if it isn't true?
如果是家族雇佣了你 他们肯定查到了那个孩子
If the family hired you,then they must have found out about the baby.
他们需要一个继承人来保存土地
They need an heir to keep their land.
而不是霜糖饼
Not the frosted cutouts.
我不吃饼干了
I will stop eating cookies.
这是我们在你身上找到的预付电话
Your prepaid cell we found on you.
你是怎么跟你另外两个同伙联系的?
How are you communicating with your other two associates?
通讯录里仅有的一个号码是6位数的
The only number stored on your contacts list is six numbers long.
你总是缺胳膊少腿的是吧?
You're always missing a couple of digits,aren't you?
也许这并不是写错的
Well,maybe that's not a mistake.
也许这是别的什么东西
Maybe it's something else.
坐标?
Coordinates?
代码?密码? - 无线频率?
- Code?Password? - Radio frequency?
无线频率
Radio frequency.
我觉得是无线频率
I'm gonna go with radio frequency.
你们永远不知道了
You will never get it now.
我们已经记下来了 聪明蛋
We wrote it down,genius.
如果他们用的是无线系统 我们应该能听到他们唠嗑
If they're using radio systems,we should be able to pick up some chatter.
来吧
**
好吧 发动
Okay,try it.
再来一次
Try it again.
就目前来看 这可是个大问题
Given the parts available,this could prove to be a problem.
这不是我们唯一的问题
that's not our only problem.
我的羊水刚刚破了
My water just broke.
我要生了
I'm going into labor.
呜啦?
Ooh-rah?
很好 你们终于搞清楚追杀孕妇 的不是政府部门了
It's good to know you no longer think the government's hunting a pregnant woman,
DiNozzo探员 但是恐怕我也不能告知 任何有关男方家那边的消息
Agent DiNozzo,but I'm afraid I can't help you apprehend the Afghan in-laws that are.
今天可是平安夜 长官
It is Christmas Eve,sir.
哼 这份礼物得由中央司令部送给你才成 里面的人可比我高个14级
Well,that gift would have to come from CENTCOM and about 14 other people above my pay grade.
哦 让我猜猜 上面还缠满了官僚主义的红丝带?
Yeah.Let me guess - it'd be wrapped in red tape?
多谢你啥也没帮上
Thanks for nothing.
枪手的无线频道里有发现
Got something from our gunman's radio frequency.
从如此微弱的信号来看 他们起码40英里以外
And given the weak signal,they got to be at least 40 miles away.
你在哪?
Where are you?
不远
Not too far.
来见我
Meet me.
吉维尔镇外的加油站 现在马上
Petrol station outside Ridgeville. Now.
听起来像是俄罗斯人
Sounds like Russians to me.
搜索吉维尔镇附近的加油站
Searching for gas stations near Ridgeville,Maryland.
地方不大
Pretty small town.
我找到了 15号国道边上的一家加油站
All right,I got a hit on a single service station alongside State Route 15.
他们往那里去的唯一一个理由就是
Only one reason our gunmen would go there.
Gibbs - Gibbs
- Gibbs. - Gibbs.
他们有麻烦了
They're in trouble.
那里应该就是他们被搁延的地方
It could be where they're holed up.
你们找到Gibbs探员了?
You find Agent Gibbs?
我们马上就会知道的
That's what we're gonna find out.
带上装备 McGee
Put it in gear,McGee.
祝好运
Good luck.
是啊 好运
Yeah.Good luck.
你为什么这样阴阳怪气的说话?
Why in the world would you say it like that?
为 为什么?这破天气 路都封了 他们肯定没法找到的
Wh-Why?The weather,the road closures,'cause they're never gonna make it.
你又怎么知道?
How the hell would you know?
他们都是训练有素的探员
They're trained agents.
呃...
Well...
你可以不尊重我和我们的工作
You might not respect me or what it is we do here,
但是你不能不尊重这样一个事实 这些人
but you have got to respect that fact that these people--
我们的同伴 正在冒着生命危险!
my people - are risking their lives!
呃 如果你硬要这么说的话...
Well,if you're gonna put it like that...
这是毋庸置疑的事实
There's no other way to put it.
我们哪也不去 直到你意识到这点为止
Till you can figure that out,we're not going anywhere.
坐下 然后闭嘴
Sit down and shut up.
最后两次宫缩间隔不到一分钟了
The last two were less than a minute apart.
我在摩苏尔中了榴霰弹也没那么疼
It didn't hurt this much when I took shrapnel in Mosul.
整个线路肯定是熟了
The whole harness must be sautd.
是烧了
Fried.
哦 天 宝宝要出来了!
Oh,boy,the baby's coming!
Gibbs
Gibbs.
我们有访客了
We have company.
你打算怎么做?
What do you want to do?
守住我们的领地
Defend our position.
你跟上尉一块 我去对付他们
You stay with the lieutenant; I'll draw fire.
别离开我 Gibbs
Don't you leave me,Gibbs.
我需要有人告诉我怎么做
I need someone to tell me how I'm doing.
你表现得很好
You're doing fine.
我可不确定
I'm not so sure.
你是在要求特殊对待吗 陆战队员?
Are you asking for special treatment,Marine?
长官 是的 长官
Sir,yes,sir.
就这一次
Just this once.
嘿 Gibbs?
Hey,Gibbs?
没问题 我去掩护
It's okay. Got this covered.
谢谢
Thank you.
你可能需要抓住这个
You might want to hold off on that.
用力
Push.
再用力
他还好吗?
Is he okay?
她很漂亮
She's beautiful.
是个女孩?
It's a girl?
她的眼睛跟你一样
She's got her mom's eyes.
做的好 陆战队员
Well done,Marine.
哦 圣诞快乐 McGee探员 DiNozzo探员
Oh,merry Christmas,Agent McGee,Agent DiNozzo.
嘿 Breena
Hey,Breena.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
你们见到Jimmy和我爸爸了吗?
Have you seen Jimmy or my dad?
他们昨晚没回家
They never came home last night.
我猜他们被案子困住了?
Guess they got caught up in the case,huh?
怎么回事?
What's going on?
今天几号?
What day is it?
今天是圣诞节 爸爸 你没错过
It's Christmas,Dad.You didn't miss it.
哦 天
Oh,boy.
他...他们回来啦? 发生了什么?
Th... They're back?What's happening?
上尉没事吗?
Lieutenant okay?
孩子呢?
What about the baby?
她们在医院 母女平安
They're at the hospital; mother and child are fine.
啥?都平安?
What?They're okay?
哦...看看这个
Oh...look at that.
多可爱的小家伙
Cute little bugger.
让我想起了你 女儿
Reminds me of you,baby.
- 她真漂亮 - 她真漂亮
- She's beautiful. - She's beautiful.
如果你还搞不清为什么 我们花那么多时间
And if you're still wondering why we put in so many long hours
以及做出这么多个人牺牲...
and make so many personal sacrifices...
好 好 我已经明白了
Yeah,yeah,I get it.
我很感谢你提供给我的机会...
And while I really appreciate the offer...
但我在这里很开心
I'm very happy right here.
如果这是你想要的 而且Breena 仍旧愿意嫁给你 就算...
If that's what you want,and Breena's still willing to marry you despite...
爸爸 - 啥?
- Dad. - Yeah?
别说了
Stop.
不说了
Never.
只是别在这开太多夜车 孩子
Just don't spend too many nights here,son.
我希望你们将来也有个 可爱的小孩子
I want you two to have one of those someday.
祝你们圣诞节快乐
Merry Christmas,you two.
粉红色自行车 真漂亮 老大
Pretty pink bike,boss.
流苏挺好看的
Nice tassels.
没错
Yeah.
为Mike Franks的孙女做的
For Mike Franks' granddaughter.
啊 我忘记Amira和Leyla现在住在特区了 当然
Ah,I forgot - Amira and Leyla live in DC now.Of course.
我猜你有地儿去了
So I guess you have somewhere else to be.
没错 你也是啊
Yeah,well,so do you.
我去过了
I went.
坐在车里 自我挣扎了20分钟
Sat in the car for about 20 minutes debating.
最后没进去
I didn't go in.
决定不如来Gibbs的小屋看看
Decided to swing by Casa de Gibbs instead.
我们都有自己的决定要做 DiNozzo
Well,we all make our own choices,DiNozzo.
你觉得我做错了?
You think I made a mistake?
我觉得你又错了一次
I think you made it twice now.
当我加入NCIS的时候 我知道你对我的期望
Well,when I joined NCIS,I knew what you expected of me.
所有的期望
Everything.
我的世界便没有多少空间 留给我的Wendy们了
Doesn't exactly leave a lot of room for the Wendys of the world.
你是来这怪我的吗 DiNozzo?
Did you come here to blame me,DiNozzo?
不是 老大
No,boss.
那就好
Good.
家庭和工作
Family and job.
两个不同的杯子
Two different cups.
对
That's right.
而且 如果我无法两全 就是我自己的问题
And... if I couldn't fill both,that was my problem.
如果我现在能了呢?
What if I can now?
那就滚出我的地下室 振作点 向前走
Then get out of my basement; man up and move on.
像你那样?
Like you have?
别跟着我学
Don't be like me.
要吸取我的教训
Learn from it.
深受裨益
Good talk.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
嘿 你到底来不来?
Hey,are you coming or not?
Leyla做了羊肉
Leyla's making lamb.
呃 这合适吗?
Uh,you sure it's all right?
当然 我告诉她你会来
Yeah,I told her you were coming.
几时?
When?
上礼拜
I told her last week.
你在这下面啥也找不到的 DiNozzo
You're not gonna find what you're looking for down here,DiNozzo.
赶紧来
Come on.